Word groups and phrasing. Use punctuation for phrasing. Commas sound different from
periods. Pauses for related thoughts, ideas, or for breathing. By now, you've
begun developing a strong intonation with clear peaks and reduced valleys, so you're
ready for the next step. You may find yourself reading the paragraph like this.
Hello, my name is so-and-so. I'm taking American accent training. If so, your
audience won't completely comprehend or enjoy your presentation. In addition to
intonation, there's another aspect of speech that indicates meaning. This can be
called phrasing or tone. Have you ever caught just a snippet of a conversation in
your own language and somehow known how to piece together what came before or after
the part you heard? This has to do with phrasing. In a sentence, phrasing tells
the listener where the speaker is at the moment, where the speaker is going, and if
the speaker is finished or not. Note that the intonation stays on the nouns.